Shuya Sonoda

Full-Stack Developer

 Vancouver, BC |
 (236) 833-3181 |
 shuya.life@gmail.com |
 GitHub |
 LinkedIn

Summary

- · 2 years+ of experience in software engineering as a full-stack developer.
- 4 years of experience in product management and project management.
- · Software engineering expertise to design and build a web application.
- Product management expertise to build a strong strategy for the product, especially in the early phase.

Skills

Languages Go, PHP, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python

Front-end Vue.js, Nuxt.js, React.js, Next.js, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind CSS

Back-end REST API, GraphQL, Swagger, Stripe, Node.js, Express, Laravel, Microservices, Clean Architecture, DDD, TDD, CI/CD

Database RDB (PostgreSQL, MySQL) / NoSQL(Google Datastore, DynamoDB, MongoDB)

Infrastructure AWS, GCP, Terraform, Docker, Firebase

Testing Unit Testing, E2E Testing, Cypress

Agile and Scrum Github, Figma, Jira, Confluence, Wrike, Notion, Slack

Experience

Software Developer

Tokyo, Japan

LIFULL April 2021 - March 2023

- Systematized operations requiring complex approval flows, reducing work hours by more than 50 hours per month using Go and Vue.js.
- Designed and implemented housing platform functionality to enhance the value of the service using Go, TypeScript, PostgreSQL, and AWS.
- Reduced development costs by 20%, controlling resources in the development environment using AWS and Terraform.
- Implemented a web scraping application for the efficient collection of competitive information using TypeScript.
- Migrated legacy batches to a new environment to increase development efficiency and performance.
- Built a billing management system from scratch using Google App Script, and PostgreSQL.
- Analyzed and improved SQL that was leading to poor performance.

Software Developer, Freelance

Tokyo, Japan

habitat

June 2022 - March 2023

- Developed a customer dashboard for a hot tub reservation application using Go, GraphQL, Datastore, and AppEngine.
- Automated the modification of past data after the addition of new functions by implementing batches.
- · Implemented a sorting function based on the user's location using Google Geolocation API.
- Implemented a refund function using Go, GraphQL, and Stripe.

Product Manager, Freelance

Tokyo, Japan

moja

April 2020 - May 2022

- Successfully raised 135 million yen (approx 1,350,000 CAD) in new product planning for B2B sales automation Saas.
- Implemented the most viable product using Go, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, and Google AppEngine.
- · Designed the product design and built product strategy using Figma.

Product Manager

Tokyo, Japan

CyberAgent

April 2017 - March 2021

- Planned and launched a product for an Al-based ad monitoring system, enabling monitoring ads without human oversight.
- Launched ByteDance's joint advertising product with TikTok, and directed the development and product design.
- · Led the integration with Google's ad platform as a product manager for SSP.

Education

Cornerstone International Community College

Web and Mobile App Development Diploma

Vancouver, BC, Canada May 2023 - CURRENT

Kyushu University

Fukuoka, Japan

Bachelor of Bioresource and Bioenvironmental Sciences

April 2013 - March 2017

· Fostered analytical skills using R